<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Act for the levy. Edinburgh, the twenty third day of May 1693.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05195</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1107</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183911</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52529195</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52529195</idno>
            <idno type="VID">178891</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05195)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 178891)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2774:30)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Act for the levy. Edinburgh, the twenty third day of May 1693.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the heir of Andrew Anderson, Printer to their most excellent Majesties,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1693.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed at end: Extracted forth of the records of Parliament, by Tarbat, Cls. Regist.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Scotland. --  Army --  Recruiting and enlistment --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:178891:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 3 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:178891:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 3 -->
            <head>ACT For the Levy.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Edinburgh, <date>the twenty third day of <hi>May</hi> 1693.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>THE ESTATES OF PARLIAMENT Conſidering the preſent Dangers, and that Their Majesties may think it expedient, to Order the Levying of more Forces, for obviating the ſaid Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers: And being withall moſt ſenſible, of the Duty they own to Their Majeſties, for theſe great and manifold Bleſſings they enjoy by, and under Their Happy Government; Do for themſelves, and in Name and Behalf of Their Majeſties good Subjects within this Kingdom, by theſe Preſents, Renew the Humble and Hearty Tender of their Lives and Fortunes, for the promoting of Their Majeſties Service: And further, in Purſuance of their Duties expreſſed in the Act of Parliament 1663, entituled an Humble Ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to his Sacred Majesty, of the Duty and Loyalty of his antient Kingdom of <hi>Scotland,</hi> they do Cheerfully Offer to Their Majeſties, a preſent Levy of two thouſand nine hundred and ſeventy nine Foot, to be Levyed off the ſeveral Shyres and Burghs of this Kingdom, effeiring to proportions and numbers ſet down in the foreſaid Act. And to the end, the foreſaid Levy may be made effectual, Their Majesties with Advice and Conſent of the ſaid Eſtates of Parliament, do Order and Appoint the Shyres, Stewartries, and Burghs within this Kingdom, to put out and deliver, when they ſhall be thereto Required, and to ſuch Officers, as ſhall be Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſionat by Their Majeſties for that effect, the foreſaid proportions and numbers which are hereby appointed to be Levyed, according to the numbers formerly obſerved in the Militia, and are as follows, <hi>viz.</hi> the Shyres of <hi>Roxburgh</hi> and <hi>Selkirk,</hi> one hundred ninety eight, <hi>Berwick</hi> one hundred and nineteen, the Shyre of <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinburgh,</hi> one hundred and nineteen, <hi>Haddingtoun</hi> one hundred and nineteen, <hi>Peebles</hi> fourty, <hi>Linlith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gow</hi> fifty, the Town of <hi>Edinburgh, Leith,</hi> and <hi>Cannongate,</hi> one hundred and nineteen, <hi>Dumfreis</hi> one hundred and nineteen, the Shyre of <hi>VVigtoun</hi> fourty five, the Stewartry of <hi>Kirkcudbright</hi> ſeventy five, <hi>Air</hi> and <hi>Renfrew,</hi> one hundred ninety eight, <hi>Lanerk</hi> one hundred fourty nine, <hi>Stirling</hi> and <hi>Clackmannan</hi> one hundred, <hi>Fife</hi> and <hi>Kinroſs</hi> two hundred thirty eight, <hi>Perth</hi> two hundred thirty eight, <hi>Forfar</hi> one hundred fourty nine, <hi>Kincardine</hi> and <hi>Mariſchals</hi> part of <hi>Aberdeen,</hi> one hundred and nineteen, the reſt of <hi>Aberdeen</hi> Shyre and <hi>Bamff,</hi> one hundred fifty nine, <hi>Elgin, Nairn,</hi> and this ſide of <hi>Roſs,</hi> one hundred fourty nine, the Earl of <hi>Seaforth</hi> and Lord <hi>Lovat</hi> their Diviſion of <hi>Inverneſs,</hi> one hundred, <hi>Sutherland, Caithneſs,</hi> and the rest of <hi>Inverneſs,</hi> one hundred fifty nine, Argyle, <hi>Dumbartoun,</hi> and <hi>Bute,</hi> one hundred and nineteen, <hi>Orkney</hi> and <hi>Zetland,</hi> one hundred, to be divided and modelled into Regiments, as Their Majeſties ſhall think fit, and to be thereafter payed and maintained from the ſaids Fonds Impoſed, or to be Impoſed by this Parliament for that effect, and that by ſuch Rules of Eſtabliſhment as Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties ſhall appoint, which Levies and Proportions, the Commiſſioners of Supply, which now are, or ſhall be hereafter in the ſaid Shyres and Stewartries, with one or two Magiſtrats for each Royal Burgh, are hereby fully Impowered to make effectual. And it is hereby Provided, that where the Maſter and Tennents ſhall appoint a man one or moe to be put out in the ſaid Levies, the ſaid Perſon or Perſons may be ſeized and ſecured by the Sheriff of the Shyre, or any two or moe of the Commiſſioners of Supply, or one or two of the Magiſtrats of the reſpective Burghs for their Burgh, when ever the ſaid Officer who is to have the ſaid Perſon or Perſons comes to require them within the Shyre. Likeas, the ſaid Commiſſioners of Supply with the foreſaid Officer, are to cognoſce and determine upon the ſufficiency or inſufficiency of the men: And in regard, there have been al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terations made by the Acts of Parliament, as to the Extent and Bounds of ſome Shyres, ſince the Act of Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament one thouſand ſix hundred and ſixty three, Their Majeſties with Conſent foreſaid, do Authorize and Impower the Lords of Privy Council, to adjuſt the proportions of the ſaid Shyres, notwithstanding of theſe alterations, who are likewiſe hereby warranted, to give ſuch other Orders in this matter, as they ſhall find ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſar. And laſtly, Their Majesties do hereby graciouſly declare, that for a year and a half after the date hereof, the Militia of the Countrey, or any part thereof, is not to be called out, or made uſe of, except in the caſe of an actual Invaſion.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Extracted forth of the Records of Parliament, by <hi>TARBAT, Cls. Regiſt.</hi>
               </signed>
               <lb/>
GOD Save King <hi>William</hi> and Queen <hi>Mary.</hi>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the Heir of <hi>Andrew Anderſon,</hi> Printer to their moſt Excellent Majeſties, <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1693.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
